我们是宝石战士
We are the Crystal Gems
本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
终日拯救世界
we'll always save the day
■
时间轴： 树叶
如果你感到怀疑
and if you think we can't
我们总能找到出路
we'll always find a way
■
翻译： 树叶  陽光sunshine
所以全世界人们都信任
that's why the people of this world believe in...
■
校订： Enpistu
石榴  紫晶
Garnet, Amethyst...
和珍珠
and Pearl...
还有史蒂文
and Steven!
宇宙小子  第二季第四集
Steven Universe  S02E04  Say Uncle
阿公驾到
■
后期： 树叶  小黑
护盾
Shield.
不  不要泡泡  是护盾
No, not bubble ... shield!
我到底哪一步做错了
What am I doing wrong?
其他宝石战士都能轻易召唤武器
The gems can all summon their weapons.
我怎么就不行
Why can't I?!
有没有人能来帮帮我啊
Isn't there somebody who can help me?!
什么
Wha...
早上好
Good morning!
棒呆了
Bravo!
这家伙的闪亮登场真厉害
This guy sure knows how to make an entrance!
你说是不是  海豚先生
What do you think, Mr. Dolphin?
我的天啊  是天才阿公
Oh, my gosh! Uncle Grandpa!
真的是你  我不敢相信
You're really here! I can't believe it!
我是说  我真真儿不敢相信啊
I mean, I literally can't believe it.
这怎么可能发生
How is this even possible?!
别担心伙计  这些都不是动真格的
Don't worry, bro ... none of this is canon.
但这个是真的大炮哦
But this is!
[愚人节快乐]
噢  不  我们的船
Oh, no! Our ship!
那么  我听说你的肚子出了点小麻烦
So, I hear your belly's being a bit of a bummer.
是啊  我整个早上都在尝试
Yeah. I've been trying to pull my shield
用宝石召唤出我的护盾
out of my gem all morning.
唔  那我来仔细看看
Hmm. Well, let's take a look-see.
你最好经常擦擦这东西
You should make sure you get this thing polished
每年至少两次吧
at least twice a year.
那么  你能帮到我吗
So, do you think you can help me?
我只是很想保护我的朋友们
I just want to be able to protect my friends.
唔  没错  你得了肚子忧郁症
Hmm. Yep. It's the belly blues.
-我以前见过你这种症状  -真的吗
- I've definitely seen this before. - Really?
我当时就在你旁边啊  不记得了吗
I was there! Don't you remember?
哇哦  嘿
Whoa! Hey!
是一部超棒的新卡通耶
It's a rad new cartoon picture show!
嗨  嗨  你们好呀
Hey! Hey! Hi, there!
早上好
Hello? Hey, good morning?
我一点也想不起来了
I don't remember that at all.
所以只有当你需要保护的时候盾才会出现
So, your shield only comes out when you need to protect yourself.
-是啊  -那好办
- Yeah? - Well, then...
-只需要一些能逼你保护自己的事情
you just need something to protect yourself from ...
比如用这个狂霸酷炫拽的火箭筒
like this cool mega super awesome rocket launcher.
阿公  这个看上去不安全啊
Uh, Uncle Grandpa, this doesn't seem safe.
别担心孩子  我戴了头盔哟
Don't worry, kid ... I'm wearing a helmet.
-有发生什么吗  -啥也没有
- Anything? - No.
那再试试这个蜂箭炮
Then how about a bee-zooka?
或者毒蛇箭
Or a snake shooter?
再来蜂箭炮
Or the bee-zooka again?
还是没用啊  噢  有办法了
Hmm. Still nothin'. Oh, I know!
紫晶  你今早看见史蒂文了吗
Amethyst, have you seen Steven this morning?
有啊  他在和那个怪人一起玩呢
Yep. He's hanging out with some weirdo.
看上去他在试着让史蒂文人间蒸发呢
I think he's trying to vaporize Steven.
史蒂文啊啊啊啊啊啊
Steven!
不要泡泡  要护盾啊
No, not bubble ... shield!
唔  我就知道
Hmm. I would have sworn
这个专治懦夫末日死光炮
a doomtastic death ray of dastardly destruction
一定会有效的  还想再来点蜂箭炮吗
would have worked. You want to try the bees again?
史蒂文
Steven!
发生什么了  这陌生人是哪儿来的
What's going on? Who is this stranger?
他不是什么陌生人  是天才阿公大叔呀
He's not a stranger! He's Uncle Grandpa!
阿公  大叔
"Uncle... Grandpa?"
所以他既是格雷格的兄弟
So, that would make him Greg's brother...
-也是父亲  -那就说得通了
- and father? - That would explain a lot.
没错哟
That's right!
他不止是你的阿公  史蒂文
He's not just your Uncle Grandpa, Steven ...
他是全世界每一个人的阿公
he's everyone in the world's Uncle Grandpa!
如果他到访了
And when he comes to town,
你一定能玩得非常开心
you're sure to have a fun time!
我们在太空呢
We're in space!
救命  我的头装反了
Agh! My head is on backwards!
-紧急讨论  -很明显
- Gem huddle! - Obviously...
我们在对付一个能力超强  能扭曲现实的东西
we're dealing with some superpowerful, reality-warping entity.
他对于整个时空都是隐患
He could be a danger to the fabric of space itself.
谁知道呢  其实我还挺喜欢他的
I don't know, guys. Heh. I kind of like him.
嘿  你们几个在聊什么
Hey! What are you guys talking about?
是要组成什么秘密团体吗
Are you forming a secret club?
我们能参加吗
Can we join too?
呃  天才阿公
Um, Uncle Grandpa...
-早上好  -好
- Good morning. - Yes.
-我们刚刚决定  -打电玩
- We have decided to ... - Play video games?
-不是呃  -绕圈跑
- No. Uh ... - Run around in circles?
-不是  -吃三人三明治
- No. - Eat a three-way sub?
紫晶
Amethyst!
都不是 我们决定
No. We have decided ...
你对于史蒂文和地球来说都太危险了
That you are a danger to Steven and the Planet Earth
我们必须除掉你
and we must destroy you.
-什么  -糟糕的早晨
- What?! - Bad morning.
等等  不要  你们别伤害他
Wait! No! You guys, don't hurt him!
宝石战士队
Crystal Gems
逃兵队
Run away
来吧孩子 快跑
Come on, kid. Let's go!
怎么会
Wh-y-y-y-y-y?!
很抱歉  她们平时都不这样的
I'm sorry! They're not usually like this!
快  神奇腰包  给我们一个剧情漏洞
Quick! Belly bag, we need a plot hole!
收到  阿公
Sure thing, Uncle Grandpa!
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
早上好
Good morning!
对了  我把那孩子藏在哪里了
Now, where'd I put that little kid?
这儿呢  早上好
Oh, yeah! Good morning!
我拉你一把
Oh, let me give you a hand there.
喔  我在哪里
Whoa. Where am I?
-欢迎来到阿娱房车  -什么东西
- Welcome to the UGRV! - The wha?
阿公娱乐休闲房车
The Uncle Grandpa recreational vehicle.
哦  真酷啊  我爸爸也住在货车里
Oh, cool! My dad lives in a van, too!
-你以前是摇滚明星吗  -我仍旧是呢  孩子
- Did you used to be a rock star? - I'm still a rock star, kid.
史蒂文  我带你转转
Hey, Steven, I'll give you the tour!
哇  好大呀  这里能装下上百万辆货车
Wow! It's huge! You could fit a million vans in here!
其实也就能放四五十辆吧  你瞧
Actually, it's more like 40 or 50 vans. See?
[四五十辆货车]
你好  是我啊  披萨·史蒂夫
Oh, hey. It's just me, Pizza Steve ...
史上最酷最可口美味的史蒂夫
just the coolest and tastiest Steve who ever lived.
你好  披萨·史蒂夫  我也叫史蒂夫
Hi, Pizza Steve! I'm a Steve, too ...
-史蒂文·宇宙  -史蒂  文·宇宙
- Steven Universe. - Steve-n Universe?
好吧  阿公  我还定了两条规矩呢
Come on, Uncle G. I've got two rules ...
不得超过四五十辆车
No more than 40 or 50 vans
而且只能存在一个史蒂夫
and only one Steve allowed!
是的啊  但这个史蒂文很特别的
Yeah, but this Steven is special.
没错  他是宝石战士
Yeah! He's a Crystal Gem!
-早上好  哥斯先生  -近来可好啊  阿公
- Good morning, Mr. Gus. - What's up, Uncle Grandpa?
哇  哥斯先生  你怎么知道我的事
Whoa! Mr. Gus! How do you know about me?
我的知识面覆盖了
I have a comprehensive knowledge
多重宇宙的所有魔法生物
of all magical denizens of the multiverse.
我了解宝石战士的一切
I know all about the Crystal Gems.
来这里  伙计  看看这个
Come here, man. Check this out.
我甚至创造了自己的宝石人物
I even made my own gemsona.
我的宝石在尾巴上  武器是一个煎锅
My gem is on my tail, and my weapon is a frying pan.
-画的不错  哥斯先生  -真的超级酷  哥斯先生
- Nice line work, Mr. Gus! - That's really cool, Mr. Gus.
-我希望自己也能像你画的一样酷  -怎么了吗
- I wish I was as cool as your drawing. - Something wrong?
史蒂文不知道怎样召唤盾牌
Steven doesn't know how to summon his shield.
不会吧
You don't say?
很简单的  史蒂文继承了母亲的力量
Oh, that's simple. Steven's powers are maternal.
他对宝石的控制来源于情感认知
Control of his gem is based on emotional clarity.
他的盾牌只有在感受到某种极端情绪的时候
His shield only comes out when he's feeling extreme emotions of ...
哥斯先生  我把你的画改好了
Hey, Mr. Gus! I fixed your drawing!
嘿  你怎么不新建图层啊
Hey! Why didn't you do that on a new layer?!
你好  超写实巨型飞虎
Oh, hi, giant realistic flying tiger!
你有什么建议给史蒂文吗
You got any advice for Steven?
我还是不告诉他了  那只对猫科动物有效
I'm not gonna tell him that. That only works on cats.
那么  现在做什么
Well, now what?
我们就坐在这里  等着大事发生
We just sit here until something happens.
出大事了
Something happened!
肯定有能出去的路
There's gotta be some way out of here.
我们永远都出不去了  这是我们的新家
We'll never escape! This is our new home!
-珍珠  你太夸张了  -我才没夸张
- Pearl, you're overreacting. - I'm not overreacting!
史蒂文在哪
Hey, where's Steven?
在找我吗  披萨·史蒂文·宇宙
Looking for me, Pizza Steven Universe?
-这不是我的宝贝儿  -美味啊
- That's not my baby! - Aw, nice!
哇  等等
Whoa! Hold on!
披萨
Pizza!
不要吃披萨·史蒂夫
Don't eat Pizza Steve!
好吧  我已经准备好结束本集了
Okay. I'm ready for this episode to end.
很抱歉我没能帮你
I'm sorry I couldn't help you
学会怎么召唤盾牌  史蒂文
learn to use your shield, Steven.
没关系的  阿公  我今天很开心
It's okay, Uncle Grandpa. I had a lot of fun today.
-史蒂文  -离那个老头远点
- Steven! - Get away from that man!
他是个怪物
He's a monster!
别这样  伙伴们  他已经很沮丧了
Hey, cut it out, guys! He's down enough already!
噢  早上好
Oh, good morning!
这招好厉害
That smarts.
干掉他
Finish him!
不  不要伤害他
No! Don't hurt him!
住手
Sto-o-o-o-p!
我做到了  阿公  我真的做到了
I did it, Uncle Grandpa! I really did it!
耶
Yay!
保护他就激活了史蒂文的力量吗
Protecting him activated Steven's powers?!
他肯定真的很在乎这位陌生人
He must really care about this stranger.
希望他不是很在乎那块披萨
I hope he didn't care about that pizza.
听我说  天才阿公今天在这里露面
Listen! It was a big, weird surprise
带来了一个怪怪的大惊喜
when Uncle Grandpa showed up here today.
我们从来没有见过像阿公这样的人
We've never met anyone like Uncle Grandpa.
但对于不了解的人  我们不该随便攻击
But you can't just attack people you don't understand.
而是应该和睦相处  耐心倾听他们的话
You have to stick up for them and listen to what they have to say.
你们不也是这样对待我的吗
You guys always do that for me.
史蒂文  你说的没错
Steven, you're right.
我的目光竟然如此短浅
How could I be so blind?!
很抱歉  真的很抱歉
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
-我也为珍珠的表现道歉  -谢谢
- I also apologize for Pearl. - Thank you.
你给了我们宝贵的教训   阿公
You've taught us a valuable lesson, Uncle Grandpa.
那么  看来我的任务完成了
Welp, I think my work here is done.
拜拜
Bye-bye!
记住  孩子们  不要害怕当超级怪胎
Remember, kids ... don't be afraid to be superweird.
我和史蒂文永远支持你
Steven and I have got your back.
不要以仇恨的眼睛看世界   永远要记得说
See with eyes unclouded by hate and always remember to say...
早上好
"good morning!"
天啊  晃得我眼睛疼
Boy, that sure makes my eyes hurt.
现在来看看这个
Now let's see here.
德克斯特  蒂蒂  花花  泡泡  毛毛
Dexter, Dee Dee, Blossom, Bubbles, Buttercup,
三个艾德  比利  曼迪  麦克  朱尼珀
Ed, Edd, Eddy, Billy, Mandy, Mac, Juniper,
霹雳特警猫  阿嗨  芬恩
Swat Kats, Flapjack, Finn.
啊  还有史蒂文  那么下一个是谁呢
Ah, Steven! Now who's next?